Lemon and Mary Hine 076
People's Archive, MLK Library
Lemon and Mary Hine Papers
1855-1993
People's Archive, MLK Library
076
4 Linear feet
Custodial History
Frederick F. Wright, a descendant of Lemon and Mary Hine, donated the collection to the DC Community Archives. The donation was originally made in 2004, with subsequent additions made in 2005 and 2006.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of the incoming and outgoing correspondence of both Lemon and Mary Hine. The letters begin in the 1850s and continue to the late 1880s. Most of the letters are paired with their individual envelopes. There are also letters to and from their children and other descendants of the Hine family. Also in this collection are financial records, photographs, publications, articles, and invitations. The materials are divided into three series: Correspondence, Photographs, and Ephemera.
Politics and government
- Series 1: Correspondence
  Scope and Contents
  This series is made up, almost entirely, of the correspondence to and from Lemon and Mary Hine. There also letters to and from their children and one postcard from their descendant Richard Wright. Some correspondence contains items sent to the recipient and remained in the envelope with the letter. These items include: an 1883-dime, swatches of fabric, and locks of hair.
  - Della to Lemon, September; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Frank Hemenway to Lemon, August 13 1861 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - B. L. Hill to Lemon, May 11 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - D. M. Hine to Lemon, December 13 1856 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - H. S. Hine to Lemon, September 28 1856 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - [H. Franklick] to Lemon, September 15 1856 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - W. C. McGouigal to Lemon, January 16 1858 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Marnie to Lemon, September 5 1885 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mary to Lemon, June 16 1857 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Mary to Lemon, July 18 1857 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mary to Lemon, September 15 1857 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mary to Lemon, October 1857 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Mary to Lemon, November 26 1857 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mary to Lemon, January 4 1858 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mary to Lemon, May 19 1858 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mary to Lemon, April 17 1858 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mary to Lemon, June 8 1858 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Mary to Lemon, July 4 1858 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mary to Lemon, July 10 1858 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mary to Lemon, July 27 1858 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Mary to Lemon, August 1858 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Mary to Lemon, August 11 1858 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Mary to Lemon, September 17 1858 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Mary to Lemon, September 19 1858 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Mary to Lemon, September 30 1858 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Mary to Lemon, October 30 1858 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Mary to Lemon, November 20 1858 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Mary to Lemon, January 3 1859 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Mary to Lemon, January 8 1859 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Mary to Lemon, January 18 1859 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Mary to Lemon, March 1 1859 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Mrs. J. Hartman to Lemon, March 8 1859 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Mary to Lemon, September 28 1859 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Mary to Lemon, October 14 1859 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Mary to Lemon, November 11 1859 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Mary to Lemon, November 26 1859 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Mary to Lemon, December 19 1859 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Mary to Lemon, December 24 1859 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Mary to Lemon, December 29 1859 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Mary to Lemon, January 4 1860 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Mary to Lemon, January 12 1860 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Mary to Lemon, January 19 1860 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Mary to Lemon, January 26 1860 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Mary to Lemon, February 2 1860 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Mary to Lemon, February 10 1860 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Mary to Lemon, February 16 1860 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Mary to Lemon, March 6 1860 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Mary to Lemon, March 12 1860 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Mary to Lemon, March 17 1860 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Mary to Lemon, March 21 1860 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Mary to Lemon, March 28 1860 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Mary to Lemon, April 1 1860 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Mary to Lemon, April 6 1860 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Mary to Lemon, April 10 1860 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Mary to Lemon, April 14 1860 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Mary to Lemon, April 19 1860 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Mary to Lemon, April 22 1860 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Mary to Lemon, November 20 1860 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Mary to Lemon, December 6 1860 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Mary to Lemon, December 8 1860 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Mary to Lemon, March 7 1862 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Mary to Lemon, March 18 1862 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Mary to Lemon, April 15 1862 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Mary to Lemon, July 31 1864 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Mary to Lemon, August 7 1864 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Mary to Lemon, August 15 1864 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Mary to Lemon, October 9 1864 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Mary to Lemon, October 15 1864 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Mary to Lemon, October 16 1864 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Mary to Lemon, October 28 1866 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Mary to Lemon, August 8 1885 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Mary to Lemon, August 17 1885 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Mary to Lemon, August 25 1885 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Mary to Lemon, September 4 1885 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Mollie to Lemon, May 10 1858 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Mollie to Lemon, December 11 1859 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Lt. James S. Ransom to Lemon, January 11 1862 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Mary (and Bessie) to Marnie, July 27 1885 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Mary to Marnie, August 1 1885 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Mary to Marnie, August 11 1885 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Mary to Marnie, September 7 1885 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Lemon to James Dawson, September 11 1865 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, April 9 1855 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, July 16 1855 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, April 10 1857 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, May 8 1857 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, July 25 1857 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, August 2 1857 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, August 10 1857 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 23 1857 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 5 1857 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 27 1857 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 20 1857 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 8 1858 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 18 1858 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 26 1858 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, February 26 1858 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 10 1858 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 28 1858 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, May 1 1858 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, May 9 1858 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, May 28 1858 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, June 20 and 27 1858 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, July 5 1858 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, August 5 1858 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, August 28 1858 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 2 1858 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 28 1858 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 6 1858 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 21 1858 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 27 1858 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 12 1858 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 12 1858 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 24 1859 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, February 23 1859 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 23 1859 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 20 1859 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 4 1859 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 15 1859 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 27 1859 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 15 1860 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 21 1860 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 29 1860 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, February 5 1860 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, February 12 1860 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 7 1860 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 11 1860 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 16 1860 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 18 and 22 1860 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 25 1860 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, April 1 1860 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, April 6 1860 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, April 10 1860 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, April 13 1860 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, April 16 1860 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, April 17 1860 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, April 22 1860 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 3 1860 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 16 1860 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 21 1860 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 25 1860 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 1 1860 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 6 1860 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 9 1860 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 16 1860 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 16 1860 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 12 1861 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 14 1861 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 16 1861 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 19 1861 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 21 1861 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 25 1861 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 27 1861 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 1 1861 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 6 1861 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 9 1861 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 12 1861 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 18 1861 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 20 1861 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 27 1861 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 29 1861 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 3 1861 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 11 1861 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 21 1861 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 26 1861 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, November 30 1861 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 2 1861 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 9 1861 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 19 1861 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, December 22 1861 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 11 1862 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 18 1862 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 22 1862 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 23 1862 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 30 1862 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, February 5 1862 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, February 8 1862 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, February 9 1862 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, February 19 1862 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, February 23 1862 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, February 24 1862 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, February 26 1862 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 11 1862 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 14 1862 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 29 1862 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, April 6 1862 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, May 2 1862 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, May 10 1862 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, May 18 1862 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, May 25 1862 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, June 7 1862 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, June 15 1862 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, July 7 1862 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, July 13 1862 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, August 11 1862 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, August 14 1862 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, August 17 1862 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, August 24 1862 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, August 28 1862 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, August 31 1862 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 3 1862 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 5 1862 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 10 1862 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 15 1862 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 18 1862 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 24 1862 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 27 1862 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 2 1862 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 7 1862 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 1 1864 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, January 20 1865 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, June 13 1866 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, June 21 1866 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, July 2 1866 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, July 8 1866 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, July 23 1866 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, August 2 1866 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 6 1866 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, September 21 1866 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 2 1866 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 8 1866 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, October 24 1866 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 12 1885 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, March 14 1885 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, July 7 1885 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Lemon to Mary Tillinghast Hine, Undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Alice to Mary, October 25 1885 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Alpha to Mary, March 31 1861 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - M. A. Bassett to Mary, December 1 1861 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - M. A. Bassett to Mary, April 19 1862 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - M. A. Bassett to Mary, September 17 1862 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Julia T. Budfish to Mary, June 9 1885 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Della to Mary, December 3 1866 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Della to Mary, July 8 1885 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Emeline to Mary, June 2 1860 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Emeline to Mary, September 25 1865 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Emeline to Mary, January 13 1866 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Emeline to Mary, December 9 1866 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Emeline to Mary, March 23 1885 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Emeline to Mary, April 19 1885 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Emeline to Mary, May 17 1885 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Emeline to Mary, June 14 1885 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Emeline to Mary, June 18 1885 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Emeline to Mary, July 11 1885 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Emeline to Mary, September 1885 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Emeline to Mary, Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Emeline to Mary, September 14; Undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Frankie to Mary, August 31 1866 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Grandma to Mary, December 13 1866 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Laura to Mary, April 26 1862 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Laura to Mary, August 5 1866 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Laurie to Mary, July 10 1862 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Linda to Mary, April 6; Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Lirrie to Mary, Undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Lirrie to Mary, July 9 1860 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Lirrie to Mary, November 12 1860 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Lirrie to Mary, November 23 1860 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Lirrie to Mary, March 6 1866 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Lirrie to Mary and Oliver, May 15 1866 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Lirrie to Mary, March 30 1885 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Lirrie to Mary, April 8 1885 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Marnie to Mary, September 11 1885 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - May to Mary, Undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - MJG to Mary, February 26; Undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Mother to Mary, Undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Mother to Mary, Undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Mother to Mary, July 12; Undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - OGY to Mary, June 1 1860 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - M. Otis to Mary, October 1850 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Phebe to Mary, September 25 1860 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Phebe to Mary, September 28 1862 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Sister to Mary, December 23 1866 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, August 27 1860 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, January 10 1861 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, July 27 1861 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, April 25 1866 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, May 9 1866 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, January 24 1885 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, March 9 1885 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, May 11 1885 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, June 22 1885 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, July 7 1885 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, September 24 1885 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, October 14 1885 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, 42791 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, 42824 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Ruth Tillinghast to Mary, 42952 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Unknown to Mary, February 20 1862 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Blanche to Ollie Hine, July 29 1885 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Mary to Ollie Hine, August 3 1885 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Mary to Ollie Hine, August 28 1885 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Will to Ollie Hine, August 15 1885 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Richard Wright to W. L. Wright, January 18,1993 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Envelopes, 1858-1885 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Invitations, 1885 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Series 2: Ephemera
  This series contains financial records, calling cards, articles, and Lemon Hine's Last Will and Testament.
  - The Boy's News by C. L. Hine, May-December 1875 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "A History of the City of Washington", 1903 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Last Will and Testament - Lemon Hine, October 9 1901 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "The Old Songs Grandma Hine Sang", Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Prayer Card, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Proceedings with Reference to the Death of Lemon G. Hine, January 20 1914 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Publications of C. L. Hine, 1876-1877 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Receipts, 1866 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Simpson and Hine Real Estate and Lumber, 1856 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series 3: Photographs
  Series III consists of images of both Lemon and Mary Hine, as well as an image of their Washington, DC home "Prospect Hill." There is also an image encased in a frame that is decorated with the image of the Monitor and the Merrimac. The case is made of an early form of plastic, during the Victorian era. The man in the image is unidentified, though it may be Lemon Hine or a relative of his.
  - Lemon G. Hine, Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Mary Tillinghast Hine, Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Prospect Hill - Hine Residence, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Daguerreotype Case with image of man (possibly young Lemon G. Hine), Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)